nph.org 2017-10-20

# NPH International - Privacy Statement

|  |  |   
---|---|---  
|  |   

| 

|   
| 

| 

## Privacy Policy 

|   
---  
Getting our hands dirty in the pottery workshop.   
(NPH Dominican Rep.)   
  
NPH.org developed this Privacy Policy (the "Policy") as an extension of our commitment to help those in need, while serving our valued friends, donors, visitors, customers, and the companies, businesses and organizations they represent (collectively, "you") with the highest level of integrity. 

**IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THIS INTERNET WEBSITE (THE "NPH SITE"). WE MAY MODIFY THE POLICY FROM TIME TO TIME AND POST THOSE MODIFICATIONS HERE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE NPH SITE AFTER ANY SUCH MODIFICATION CONSTITUTES YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE MODIFIED AGREEMENT.**

  1. [Children](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#1)
  2. [Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2)
    1. [General Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2a)
    2. [Personal Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2b)
      1. [Sponsorship Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2bi)
      2. [Third Party Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2bii)
      3. [Credit Card Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2biii)
      4. [Email Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2biv)
    3. [Cookies](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#2c)
  3. [General Use and Disclosure of Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#3)
    1. [General Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#3a)
    2. [Personal Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#3b)
    3. [Cookie Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#3c)
  4. [Other Use and Disclosure of Personal Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#4)
    1. [Registration Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#4a)
    2. [Pre-Population Information](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#4b)
  5. [Security](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#5)
  6. [Merchant Services](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#6)
  7. [Community](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#7)
  8. [Terminating Your Sponsorship](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#8)
  9. [Corrections/Updates](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#9)
  10. [Contact Us](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/privacy.php#10)

* * *

  1. ### Children

Children are not eligible to become sponsors or to register at the NPH Site and we ask that minors (persons under the age of 18) do not submit any Personal Information to us. If you are a minor, you can use the NPH Site only with your parent(s) or guardian(s).

  2. ### Information

NPH.org obtains information from and about you in a number of ways, including:

    1. #### General Information

Some information ("General Information") is gathered automatically when you access the NPH Site. This General Information (which includes NPH Site pages visited, type of web browser used, type of operating system, and the domain name of your Internet service provider, and similar information) does not identify you personally. 

    2. #### Personal Information

Some information that may be identifiable as yours (your "Personal Information") is not gathered automatically at the NPH Site. If you wish to provide Personal Information, you must do so voluntarily, and may do so in a number of ways. The following are some of the kinds of Personal Information NPH.org gathers:

      1. #### Sponsorship Information

If you decide to register at the NPH Site as a sponsor, you will be asked for certain Personal Information, such as your name, your address, work and home telephone numbers, your email address, preferences regarding sponsorship: (1) male or female child; (2) age of the child; (3) amount and frequency of sponsorship donation; and (4) other information;

      2. #### Third Party Information

When you register at a third party website and provide Personal Information to such third parties, NPH.org may (pursuant to agreements between NPH.org and those third parties) obtain such information to populate NPH Site registration forms for use when you hyperlink to the NPH Site;

      3. #### Credit Card Information

If you elect to participate as a sponsor and choose to provide your donation via a credit card payment at the NPH Site, you will be asked for credit card information, including your name, account number and expiration date. Credit card information is stored and protected separate from your Personal and Sponsorship Information; and

      4. #### Email Information

When you send us email messages, we may retain the content of your email messages, together with your email address and our response to you.

    3. #### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a users web browser on the hard drive of a users computer. Cookies can "remember" what information ("Cookie Information") a user accesses on one web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that website by the same user, or can use that information to streamline the users transactions on related websites. The Cookies NPH.org uses do not capture your individual email address or any personally identifying information, but do permit NPH.org to send focused advertising and marketing materials, new services, promotions or other such responses to you or to assist you with your use of the NPH Site. NPH.org may also set Cookies when you register or when you acquire goods or services from the NPH Site, and may do so without notice to or permission from you or any third party. Third party websites which are accessible from the NPH Site via links, banner ads, or "click-throughs" may also use Cookies, and NPH.org shall have no responsibility whatsoever for such Cookies.

  3. ### General Use and Disclosure of Information

NPH.org uses and discloses your information that it collects as follows:

    1. #### General Information

NPH.org uses and discloses General Information to understand NPH Site demographics and content preferences, and shall do so without notice to, or permission from, you or any third party. In particular, NPH may provide aggregate information about our customers, sales, NPH Site traffic patterns and related information to our affiliates or third parties;

    2. #### Personal Information

As further provided in Section 3 ("Other Use and Disclosure of Personal Information"), NPH uses Personal Information for purposes of administering NPH charitable activities. This may include, but is not limited to, directed communications to donors, distribution of newsletters, invitations to special events, to prepare internal reports, to maintain donor/sponsorship files, and to assist with responses to your questions and concerns. NPH.org may also use and disclose Personal Information to notify you about important changes to the NPH Site or our charitable services and activities; and

    3. #### Cookie Information

NPH.org uses Cookie Information to improve the NPH Site and better serve you and those in need, and may do so without notice to, or permission from, you or any third party.

  4. ### Other Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

NPH.org respects your privacy and does not rent, sell or release Personal Information collected at the NPH Site. NPH.org may share names and addresses of sponsors with NPH.org affiliated orphanages, Nuestros Pequeños Hermanos™ for use solely in connection with acknowledgements, newsletters, and invitation mailings. We may also disclose any of your information when legally compelled to do so, or when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights. The following are some of the ways in which we may use or disclose your Personal Information to third parties:

    1. #### Registration Information

NPH.org may transfer the Personal Information you provide to NPH.org during the NPH Site registration process to affiliated third parties for those parties to use to populate their own website registration forms when you hyperlink from the NPH Site to their websites, to save you time in completing their registration forms. Such third party websites may include websites that are owned by third parties or that are "co-branded" sites of NPH.org;

    2. #### Pre-Population Information

When you come to the NPH Site from a third party website, or when you hyperlink from the NPH Site to a third party website, and in either case provide Personal Information at that third party website, NPH.org may obtain that Personal Information (pursuant to an agreement between NPH.org and that third party), and use that Personal Information to populate the NPH Site registration forms in order to save you time in completing NPH Site registration forms; and

  5. ### Security

You understand and agree that "perfect" security does not exist anywhere, including the Internet. When you send credit card information to us at the Site, we use a technology called Secure Socket Layer (SSL) or Secure Electronic Transaction (SET) to encrypt this information between your computer and our server. Other personal information you send to us at the NPH Site, however, including any email messages, will not be encrypted unless we advise you otherwise.

  6. ### Merchant Services

You may be able to access certain information related to third parties at the NPH Site, or via links, banner ads, or "click-throughs" from the NPH Site, regarding the goods or services of third parties (collectively, "Merchant Services"). You understand and agree that your access to or use of Merchant Services is a matter entirely between you and the associated third parties, and NPH.org shall have no liability whatsoever for any such access or use. Additionally, organizations such as igive.org will not disclose a donors name or other Personal Information collected at the Merchants Site to NPH.org without your prior written permission.

  7. ### Community

NPH.org urges you to use discretion when sharing Personal Information in community areas on the NPH Site such as message boards, mailing lists and directories. If you disclose Personal Information in such areas, you understand and agree that such Personal Information may be used and disclosed by others without restriction.

  8. ### Terminating Your Sponsorship

To terminate your sponsorship, send a message to the fundraising office that handles your sponsorship through the "Contact Us" page. You may continue to receive email communications for a short period of time until we have updated all of our databases. After termination of your sponsorship, your Personal Information may remain on our archived database and records for a reasonable time.

  9. ### Corrections/Updates

NPH.org gives you the opportunity to change and modify information previously provided to the NPH Site at [our contact page](https://www.nph.org/ws/contact/).

  10. ### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the NPH Site, you may contact us at [info@nph.org](mailto:info@nph.org) or write to us at: 

> Nuestros Pequeños Hermanos™ International A.C.  
> Apdo. Postal 333  
> 62000, Cuernavaca, Morelos  
> Mexico 

* * *
